Guide to the Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
- Series IV. Outgoing Correspondence
  - 1931-1937
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to [?] Willett, Sept. 19, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 33)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "Dear Mr. Willett / I mislaid this play: it has only just turned up. I shall not steal it;"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Sept. 24, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 34)
      London; begins "Dear John Farleigh / Call it £200 in round figures"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Allan Wade, Sept. 30, 1932; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 35)
      London; begins "NO: I'm a practitioner, not a professor. / Besides, you'd have to take the Albert Hall"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Oct. 17, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 36)
      London; begins "Dear John Farleigh / I don't think it would do any harm to print"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Oct. 26, 1932; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 37)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "I have only just received Micah / and Pavloff"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Oct. 30, 1932; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 38)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "It is Sunday; and the letter / containing the"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Oct. 31, 1932; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 39)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "I think the carrion bird / was a mistake of mine."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Nov. 8, 1932; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 40)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "I see no harm in exhibiting a / selection"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Nov. 9, 1932; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 41)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "Page 58 is horrid. I shall / write in 20 lines"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Nov. 13, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 42)
      London; begins "Dear John Farleigh / At last the book has gone to press."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Nov. 30, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 43)
      London; begins "Dear John Farleigh / Many thanks for the proofs."
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Colonel Lynch, Dec. 6, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 44)
      London or Ayot St. Lawrence; on physics; begins "Dear Colonel Lynch / As I am not a mathematician, propositions expressed in algebraic"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Gene Tunney [initialed], Dec. 12, 1932; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 45)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "We start for our cruise round the"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch [initialed], Dec. 18, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 46)
      Naples; begins "Please make a careful transcript of"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch [initialed], Feb. 10, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 47)
      Empress of Britain; begins "My dear Blanche / Everything has gone so far"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, July 13, 1933; calling card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 48)
      London; begins "This is an indication that you have hit / French taste"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Frank F. Bennell [initialed], July 14, 1933; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 49)
      Handwritten note in Shaw's hand at bottom; London; begins "Mr. Bernard Shaw, who is not and never has been a / professional lecturer, is now obliged to restrict his appearances / as a public speaker to special and exceptional occasions,"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Dodd, Mead & Co., Sept. 22, 1933; photocopy; 2 leaves (Box 15, Folder 50)
      With notes in hand of Dan H. Laurence; gift of Dan H. Laurence; see his Typed Letter Signed to J. Tyler of Feb. 25, 1989; London; begins "Dear Dodds both, Chase, Mead's Ghost, Lewis, old Uncle Tom"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Nov. 16, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 51)
      Requests poster design for On The Rocks; London; begins "Dear John Farleigh / Are you any good at posters?"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Nov. 28, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 52)
      London; begins "My dear Farleigh / I am horrified: I thought I had sent"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Jan. 6, 1934; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 53)
      London; begins "I nearly died when I was told / that 'the printer had'"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Jan. 14, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 54)
      London; begins "Dear John Farleigh / The enclosed is all I can get out of the"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Edgar Jepson Jr., Feb. 5, 1934; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 55)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "I got the book safely in September;"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch [initialed], Feb. 9, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 56)
      Begins "approaching Plymouth / Dead calm sea so far."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Gregg M. Sinclair, Feb. 22, 1934; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 15, Folder 57)
      RMS Rangitane; begins "Dear Mr. Sinclair / Thanks for the photographs. I have"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Sydney Carroll, June 9, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 58)
      London; begins "Dear Sydney Carroll / What can you do for me in the way of dates?"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Sydney Carroll, Aug. 13, 1934; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 59)
      Malvern; begins "The experiment with popular prices at the Winter Garden was not very encouraging"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter: to Dodd, Mead & Co. [shorthand], Sept. 10, 1934; 3 leaves + 2 (Box 15, Folder 60)
      Includes carbon copy of the transcription; London; begins "Dear Dodd Mead / I am so bewildered by the unexpected turns American publishing"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to J.B. Booth, Sept. 14, 1934; 1 leaf + envelope + 1 (Box 15, Folder 61)
      With dealer's description about contents; purchased 12/94; London; begins "Dear Mr. Booth / I am glad you destroyed the letters."
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Stanley Unwin, Nov. 8, 1934; 1 leaf + typed description (Box 15, Folder 61A)
      London; begins "Dear Stanley Unwin / The twelve and sixpenny omnibus has been sold out for a long time."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Simon & Schuster, publishers [draft of cable], Dec. 10, 1934; 1 leaf + 1 (Box 15, Folder 62)
      The date appears to be in the hand of Blanche Patch; begins "Impossible the deal is off"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch [initialed], Dec. 14, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 63)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "I have nothing to do with your Income Tax:"
    - GBS: Typed Letter: to Sir Francis Younghusband, Dec. 28, 1934; 2 leaves + 1 (Box 15, Folder 64)
      Corrections in the hand of Blanche Patch; with explanatory note on separate leaf; begins "Dear Sir Francis / I start for a trip round South America on the 16th, and am not / due back until the 1st April."
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to I.W. Prior, Jan. 19, 1935; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 15, Folder 65)
      London; begins "Dear Sir, Do not let yourself be drawn into an argument."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch [initialed], Feb. 11, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 66)
      Balboa; begins "Dear B.P. / I find that I forgot to tear off"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Sydney Carroll, Feb. 16, 1935; 2 leaves (Box 15, Folder 67)
      Includes explanatory note on separate leaf; London; begins "Dear Sydney Carroll / Many thanks; but don't waste two first night stalls on an extinct pressman"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, Apr. 5, 1935; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 68)
      Begins "In the Red Sea / All well so far. Letters received duly at"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Victor Barnowsky, Sept. 26, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 68.5)
      London; Dear Mr. Barnowsky/ All the directors who have suffered in the abominable persecution in Germany
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], May 30, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 69)
      This letter is on the same sheet as the letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; London; begins "I have this record. It is quite"
    - GBS: Typed Letter: to I.W. Prior, June 17, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 70)
      The letter was typed and signed by Shaw's secretary, Blanche Patch; London; begins "Dear Mr. Prior / Mr. Bernard Shaw asks me to say that it is impossible"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to ? [initialed], June 22, 1936; card + clipping; 3 leaves (Box 15, Folder 71)
      The clipping advertises an amateur performance of Shaw's You Never Can Tell in Egypt; includes a note by Bernard F. Burgunder; London; begins "I have written to Routledge that the matter"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Sydney Carroll, June 22, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 72)
      London; begins "My dear Sydney Carroll / Have you ever asked yourself this momentous question?"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to [Dr.?] Forbath, July 10, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 73)
      Shaw discusses his "public" and "private" handwriting, giving examples of both; London; begins "Dear [Dr.] Forbath / My secretary has discovered the enclosed soiled scraps of my handwriting / 40 years"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Hannen Swaffer, Aug. 7, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 74)
      Primarily on the Labour Party and British Politics; Malvern; begins "Dear Hannen Swaffer / I must send you a belated"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Aug. 16, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 75)
      This letter is on the same sheet as the letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; Malvern; begins "The main suggestion that occurs to"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Hannen Swaffer, Aug. 21, 1936; 2 leaves (Box 15, Folder 76)
      On the British party system; Malvern; begins "Dear Hannen Swaffer / I am kept so busy here that it ends"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Gene Tunney [initialed], Sept. 5, 1936; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 77)
      Malvern; begins "We shall be wandering in Wales until the"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Gene Tunney [initialed], Sept. 5, 1936; copy; postcard (Box 15, Folder 78)
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Sept. 23, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 79)
      This letter is on the same sheet as the letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; London; begins "May I have a look at these scripts first?"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Sept. 23, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 79)
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Gene Tunney, Oct. 17, 1936; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 15, Folder 80)
      Letter is on the sheet bearing printed instructions "From London to Ayot St. Lawrence By Road"; London; begins "My dear Gene / We shall be at Ayot as above until Thursday the 22nd."
    - GBS: Typed Letter: to I.W. Prior, Oct. 27, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 81)
      Typed and signed by Shaw's secretary, Blanche Patch; London; begins "Dear Sir, Mr. Bernard Shaw asks me to say that the practice"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company, Nov. 21, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 82)
      This letter is on the same sheet as the letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; London; begins "Yes. But unless you can get"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to George Macy, Jan. 28, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 83)
      Concerns the projected Limited Editions Club edition of Charles Dickens' Great Expectations; London; begins "Dear Mr. Macy / It is utterly impossible to print my preface"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Feb. 27, 1937; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 84)
      London; begins "No 1 absolutely barred. I agree with the / lady who"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, May 27, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 85)
      Sidmouth; begins "Dear John Farleigh / I am corresponding with Macy"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Ada Tyrrell, June 8, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 86)
      With explanatory note on separate leaf by Bernard F. Burgunder; London; begins "My dear Addie, You certainly have had a narrow escape from"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to I. William Prior, June 22, 1937; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 87)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "No. Yes. Please delete which is not applicable."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, June 23, 1937; card; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 88)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "I am off to Eastbourne for all / next week"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company, July 19, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 89)
      The B.B.C. wants to broadcast Act III from The Millionairess; this letter is on the same sheet as the letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; London; begins "No: I absolutely bar anything short of a complete broadcast"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Aug. 18, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 90)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "Dear John Farleigh / Words cannot express my"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Aug. 19, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 91)
      This letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; on the same sheet is an additional note by Shaw in a difference color ink; London; begins "O.K."
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Sept. 1, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 92)
      This letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; Sidmouth; begins "O.K. The cathedral scene"
    - No Box 15, folder 93 (Box 15, Folder 93)
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to A.J. Smith [initialed], Oct. 31, 1937; postcard; 1 leaf + 1 (Box 15, Folder 94)
      Includes note of explanation by Blanche Patch; Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "Very kind of you: but it must"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [Hamilton Marr] [initialed], Dec. 22, 1937; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 15, Folder 95)
      Notes by Shaw on a B.B.C. production of Saint Joan; Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "Schools may mean either sixth"
  - 1938-1943
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Vernon Bartlett [initialed], 1938; card; 1 leaf + 1 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      London; note on one of Shaw's specially printed postcards; with a note by Bernard F. Burgunder; begins "We are both quite well (for our ages) and Mrs. Shaw bids me not forget"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Jan. 28, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 2)
      London; begins "I had a big job to finish and / had to forget everything"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company, Mar. 17, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 3)
      London; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; begins "O.K. But in future, if I am to"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Mar. 19, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 4)
      This letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; begins "No objection."
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to James Habgood, Mar. 26, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 5)
      London; begins "Dear Sir, I remember your father very well; but we were not in"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Apr. 7, 1938; 1 leaf + 1 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      London; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; also attached is a note by Blanche Patch[?] on one of Shaw's compliments cards; begins "Send it to them by all means."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Apr. 16, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 7)
      London; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; begins "Why this appalling cut in"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company, Apr. 21, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 8)
      London; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; begins "Hooray! Terms accepted. Go ahead."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, May 5, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 9)
      London; begins "I have got muddled about those / drawings. I held back those"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], May 10, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "Geneva is finished as far as the / dialogue is concerned."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Sydney Carroll [initialed], May 12, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 11)
      London; begins "What about the third act, which requires a practicable sea?"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh [initialed], June 2, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 12)
      London; begins "The missing drawings have / been found."
    - Shaw, Charlotte (Payne-Townshend): Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff, June 10, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 13)
      London; begins "I am instructed"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff, June 15, 1938; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 16, Folder 14)
      London; dictated to Charlotte F. Shaw, and written by her; begins "Dear Ayliff / This afternoon I sent over a copy of Geneva"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], June 29, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 15)
      London; begins "On page 94, line 10, change / the word lake to park."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], June 30, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 16)
      London; begins "I strongly approve of the Lohengrin / idea."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], July 14, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 17)
      London?; begins "My dear Ayliff / Don't bother to call- unless you'd like to."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company, July 16, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 18)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "In reply to your AP/RGW"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], July 23, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 19)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "As much music as you like"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Aug. 17, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 20)
      London; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from M.T. Candler for the B.B.C.; begins "O.K.; but tell the announcer that I am professionally"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch [initialed], Aug. 24, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 21)
      Droitwich; begins "Please send me the last"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, Aug. 25, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 22)
      Droitwich; begins "Dear John Farleigh / Nothing more exactly right"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company, Sept. 15, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 23)
      Droitwich; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; begins "O.K. Go ahead; but the last"
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to George Macy, Oct. 10, 1938; 1 leaf + 3 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      London; with this are filed 3 printed items, all concerning the Limited Editions Club edition of Back to Methuselah: 1) The Monthly Letter of the Limited Editions Club, July 1939; 2) With the advice of G.B.S.; 3) "Back to Methuselah": an announcement by the Leicester Galleries of an exhibit of John Farleigh's drawings
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch [initialed], Oct. 25, 1938; card; 2 items (Box 16, Folder 25)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; the second card orders Miss Patch to disregard the information on the first; begins "I am too old to learn new"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], Nov. 7, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 26)
      Ayot St. Lawrence?; begins "Dear Ayliff / This is a masterly cut if you want"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], Nov. 9, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 27)
      London; begins "No: let Flanco alone."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], Nov. 19, 1938; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 28)
      London; begins "If you are satisfied, I shant / intrude,"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], Nov. 29, 1938; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 16, Folder 29)
      London?; begins "My dear Ayliff / The enclosed is out-and-out important."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Dec. 2, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 30)
      London; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; begins "This raises the question of the translation."
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff, Dec. 11, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 31)
      London?; begins "Dear Ayliff, What a horrible play! Why had I to"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], Dec. 22, 1938; card; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 16, Folder 32)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; begins "I forgot the stage staff this time."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter: to Gladys Storey [shorthand draft], ca. 1939; 6 leaves (Box 16, Folder 33)
      "Kate" is Kate Perugini, the daughter of Charles Dickens. The story is of Dickens's relationship with his wife; also included are 2 typed transcriptions of the draft by Blanche Patch, a Typed Letter Signed from Dan Laurence to Miss Patch requesting a transcription, and a typed copy of a letter from Kate Perugini to Shaw requesting an interview for Miss Storey (October 1927); begins "Dear Miss Story [sic] / As Kate decided to tell the story that way, told so it must be in any"
    - GBS: Typed Letter: to I.W. Prior, Jan. 19, 1939; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 16, Folder 34)
      London; the letter was typed and signed by Shaw's secretary, Blanche Patch; begins "Dear Sir, Mr. Bernard Shaw asks me to say that he has no idea"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], Jan. 27, 1939; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 35)
      London; begins "Flanco will be all right for a long / time yet."
    - GBS: Typed Letter Signed: to Hesketh Pearson [fragment], Feb. 20, 1939; copy; 3 leaves + envelope (Box 16, Folder 36)
      Text concerns Henry Arthur Jones; included with this facsimile are a letter addressed to Shaw by Jones's daughter, and a notation by Jones himself concerning Shaw; begins "The clique that abhorred me is long since dead; and as I cannot find the name of the club"
    - GBS: Autograph Note Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Feb. 18, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 37)
      London; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; begins "O.K.; but you will"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], Feb. 24, 1939; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 38)
      London; begins "It is an astonishing fact that I / have never seen S.H."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to Henry Kiell Ayliff [initialed], Feb. 28, 1939; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 39)
      London; begins "The copy you sent me does not / contain the cuts."
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company, Mar. 7, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 40)
      London; Shaw gives some suggestions on casting a performance of Candida by the B.B.C.; this letter is on the same sheet as a letter to Shaw from Hamilton Marr for the B.B.C.; begins "O.K. Phyllis Neilson Terry and"
    - GBS: Autograph Letter Signed: to British Broadcasting Company [initialed], Apr. 2, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 16, Folder 41)